[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Complete the sentence. When considering agile development, Architecture to Support Project will identify what products the Enterprise needs, the boundary of the products, and what constraints a product owner has; this defines the Enterpriseâ€™s ______________.",
    "options": [
      "operations",
      "lifecycle economics",
      "backlog",
      "workflow management"
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Who is responsible for the oversight of structures and mechanisms that drive enterprise governance of information and technology (EGIT)?",
    "options": [
      "Individual business units",
      "External regulators",
      "The board"
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "COBIT defines stakeholder value creation as which of the following?",
    "options": [
      "Realization of benefits at a controlled resource cost while controlling risk",
      "Realization of benefits at an optimal resource cost while optimizing risk",
      "Realization of benefits at a reduced resource cost while mitigating risk"
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "The value that I&T delivers should be:",
    "options": [
      "aligned directly with the values on which the business is focused.",
      "focused exclusively on I&T investments that generate financial benefits.",
      "restricted to maintaining and increasing value derived from existing I&T investments."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "COBIT addresses governance issues by doing which of the following?",
    "options": [
      "Grouping relevant governance components into objectives that can be managed to a required capability level",
      "Providing a full description of the entire IT environment within an enterprise",
      "Defining specific governance strategies and processes to implement in specific situations"
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which of the following is a guiding principle in the development of COBIT?",
    "options": [
      "COBIT aligns with other related and relevant I&T standards, frameworks and regulations",
      "COBIT includes relevant content from other related I&T standards, frameworks and regulations.",
      "COBIT serves as a comprehensive standalone framework that covers all relevant I&T-related activities."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which of the following is an element of governance?",
    "options": [
      "Building plans to align with the direction set by the governance body",
      "Monitoring activities designed to achieve enterprise objectives",
      "Evaluating stakeholder needs to determine enterprise objectives"
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "In most cases, management of the enterprise is the responsibility of:",
    "options": [
      "the project management office.",
      "the executive management team.",
      "the board of directors."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which of the following benefits derived from the use of COBIT is PRIMARILY associated with an external stakeholder?",
    "options": [
      "COBIT provides guidance on how to organize and monitor the performance of I&T across the enterprise.",
      "COBIT helps to manage the dependency on the use of external service providers.",
      "COBIT helps to ensure compliance with applicable rules and regulations."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "The primary target audience for COBIT is:",
    "options": [
      "anyone responsible for the governance solution.",
      "assurance professionals responsible for evaluating and reporting on the existence of internal controls.",
      "business and IT management responsible for building and deploying I&T solutions."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Within the principles for a governance system, the value generated from the use of I&T reflects:",
    "options": [
      "the ratio of costs versus achieved service levels.",
      "a balance among benefits, risk and resources.",
      "maximized financial benefits to the investment portfolio."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  }
]
